There it is!
（圭一(けいいち)）あった…
Hinamizawa worker lynch death
There really was one...
やっぱり あったんだ…
（トタンの へこむ音）
アッ…
ウワーッ！
（圭一）いてて…
（ﾚﾅ）あっ！ ああっ…
Are you okay? Are you?
（ﾚﾅ）大丈夫かな？ かな？
アア… いや ビビった
You scared me.
“オノとかがあると便利だ”って
言ったじゃない　それで…
You said an axe or
something would be helpful.
So...
Looks like you
brought a big one...
すげえのを持ってきてくれたけど…
（圭一）もうすぐ日が落ちるから
続きは あしただな
...but since it's getting dark,
let's continue tomorrow.
Okay...
（圭一）
何しょんぼりしてるんだよ？
Don't be sad. You'll get
to dig out Kenta tomorrow.
あしたには
ケンタくんが掘り出せるんだぜ
（ﾚﾅ）
あっ… そうだよね フフフッ！
You're right.
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Two, The Secret
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
（圭一）祭り？
（魅音(みおん)）この前 言ったじゃん
- Festival?
- I told you.
綿流しのお祭り
The Cotton Drifting Festival.
（魅音）梨花(りか)ちゃんは
そのお祭りの実行委員さんなの
Rika-chan's on the festival's
executive committee, right?
ねっ？
（梨花）はいです
Yes.
（圭一）ふ～ん…
So what's
the Cotton Drifting Festival?
…で
その“綿流し”って何なんだ？
It's where we take worn-out
blankets or padded kimonos...
（魅音）傷んで使えなくなった
お布団とかドテラとかにね
“ご苦労さま”って感謝して
供養しながら沢に流すお祭りなの
...thank them, and hold a memorial
service down the stream.
Sounds like a boring festival.
なんか退屈そうなお祭りだな
It'll be far from boring!
We'll do it again this year!
退屈どころか… 今年も やるぜ！
（４人）綿流し祭 四凶爆闘！
Cotton Drifting Festival!
Battle of Four Evils!
What's that?
何だ？ それ
（梨花）圭一も いますから
今年は五凶爆闘になりますです
Since you'll be with us, it'll be
the Battle of Five Evils this year.
Five?
（圭一）五？
（沙都子(さとこ)）おーほっほっほっ…
You're going to show off the skills
you've honed in our club.
日ごろの部活で培った実力を
ご披露するのでございますわ
つまり 露店巡りをしながら
部活動をするわけです
In other words, we'll do club
activities while visiting stalls.
（圭一）なるほど…
I see.
Yeah!
（圭一）こんにちは
（富竹(とみたけ)）うん？
Hello!
（富竹）
おや また会ったね 圭一君
Nice to see you again.
（圭一）どうも
（魅音）いい写真は撮れてますか？
Same to you.
Take any good pictures?
（富竹）まあ そこそこにね
A few, I suppose.
しかし 圭一君も隅に置けないね
両手に花で 羨ましいな
Anyway,
you're popular, Keiichi-kun.
I envy you being
surrounded by girls.
（ﾚﾅ･魅音）あっ…
（圭一）ああ いや そんな…
No, it's not like that.
Will you be staying for the Cotton
Drifting Festival this year?
（魅音）おじさま
今年は綿流しまで滞在ですか？
（富竹）うん そのつもりだよ
That's the plan.
お祭りをひととおり撮影したら
また東京に帰るよ
I'll go back to Tokyo after
taking pictures of the festival.
（ﾚﾅ）
早く写真が賞取れるといいですね
I hope you win awards
for your photos soon.
Oh, man...
まいったな ハハッ…
Well, I'll see you
again at the festival.
じゃ お祭りで また会おうね
（魅音）さようなら
Goodbye.
You all know Tomitake-san?
みんなは
富竹さんのことを知ってるんだ？
He comes here
two or three times a year.
年に２～３回 雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に来るんだよ
He takes pictures of seasonal
scenery and wild birds.
（ﾚﾅ）季節の風景や
野鳥を撮影してるんだってね
（圭一）野鳥か…
Wild birds, huh?
（圭一）それから数日がたち
綿流しの祭りの日がやって来た
A few days later, the day of the
Cotton Drifting Festival arrived.
こんにちはですよ みんな
Hello, everyone.
Wow, very nice!
（魅音）ウオッ！ いいね いいね！
（沙都子）
今年も決まっていましてよ！
You look great this year too.
So cute!
I want to take you home!
かぁいい！ お持ち帰り～！
じゃ 早速 いこうか！
So let's get started!
Yeah!
They're at it.
おお やってる やってる！ よし…
All right.
屋台 軒並み 早食い勝負！
（シャッター音）
Eating contest at
the nokinami stand!
冷たいよ…
（シャッター音）
I won't lose!
負けないですわよ！
（シャッター音）
There!
それ！
（シャッター音）
Hooray!
わあ！
（男性Ａ）
そ～っとだよ 沈まないようにね
（圭一）“綿流し”か
Cotton drifting, huh?
（ﾚﾅ）体についてた悪いものを
綿が吸い取ってくれて…
The cotton absorbs all
the bad stuff from your body.
Then we throw the cotton
into the stream, and that's it.
その綿を沢に流して おしまい
（圭一）ふ～ん…
…っと レナのヤツ
どこに行っちゃったんだ？
Huh? Where did Rena go?
Tomitake-san!
（圭一）富竹さん！
（富竹･鷹野(たかの)）あっ…
Hey, where's everyone?
（富竹）あれ？ みんなは？
（圭一）はぐれちゃって
We got split up.
Well, Keiichi-kun?
Did you enjoy the festival?
（鷹野）どうだった？ 圭一君
お祭りは楽しめた？
えっ？ あっ まあ…
I guess.
そう フフッ…
（圭一）誰だっけ？ この人
Really.
Who is this person?
Weren't you able to become
a part of Hinamizawa?
（鷹野）これで あなたも雛見沢の
人間になれたんじゃないかしら？
（圭一）どうなんでしょうね？
I'm not sure.
There still seems
to be a lot I don't know.
まだ 俺の知らないこと
いっぱいあるみたいだし
雛見沢のことでかい？
About Hinamizawa?
Like about the dam construction.
例えば ダム工事のこととか…
雛見沢が水没するとかって
大事件だったんですよね？
Hinamizawa was
almost underwater.
It was a huge incident, wasn't it?
（富竹）ダムの計画が始まったのは
７～８年くらい前かな
The dam plans started
about seven to eight years ago.
It seemed Hinamizawa and areas
upstream would be submerged.
この雛見沢から
ず～っと上流の辺りまでが―
全部 沈むことになったらしい
（圭一）そんな大規模な…
That much?
Of course protests occurred.
（富竹）当然 反対運動が起こった
裁判にもなったし―
It went to court, and scandals
and corruption were discovered.
それに絡む いろいろな不祥事や
汚職も発覚してね
ややこしいことになっているうちに
工事中止が決まったんだそうだよ
While all this took place...
...I heard they decided
to cancel construction.
Um, there was
a dismemberment, right?
あの… バラバラ殺人って
ありましたよね？
There was.
あったよ
ちょうど４年前の今ごろだったかな
It was about four years ago,
around this time of year.
During the Cotton
Drifting Festival too.
あれも 確か綿流しの日だったね
It seems the elders didn't doubt
it was Oyashiro-sama's curse.
お年寄りたちは オヤシロさまの
たたりだと疑わなかったみたいね
オヤシロさまのたたり？
Oyashiro-sama's curse?
It was thought that
Hinamizawa's guardian god...
（富竹）雛見沢を
水没させようとするダム工事に―
守り神さまがバチを
当てたってことなんだろうけど
...punished the dam construction
trying to submerge the village.
（鷹野）その後ね 毎年 起こるのよ
Since then,
it's happened every year.
（圭一）“起こる”って 何が？
Happened? What has?
Every year, someone dies the day
of the Cotton Drifting Festival.
（富竹）
毎年 綿流しの日になるとね…
誰かが死ぬんだよ
えっ… 毎年？
E-Every year?
うん
バラバラ殺人の翌年(よくとし)の綿流しの日
During the festival
a year after the murder...
...a resident of Hinamizawa
who was a dam proponent...
雛見沢の住人でありながら
ダムの誘致派だった男が―
...died on vacation when he fell
into the water under a cliff.
旅行先で
崖下の濁流に転落して死亡した
奥さんに至っては
死体も上がってない
His wife's corpse
hasn't been found.
（鷹野）更に翌年 綿流しの晩
Further, on festival
night a year later...
...a shrine priest suddenly
died of an unknown illness.
今度は神社の神主が
原因不明の奇病で急死したの
His wife drowned herself
in a swamp the same night.
奥さんは
その晩のうちに 沼に入水自殺
Further, again on
festival night the next year...
（富竹）
更に翌年　これもまた 綿流しの晩
...this time, a local housewife
was found beaten to death.
今度は
近所の主婦が撲殺体で発見された
（圭一）主婦？
（鷹野）被害者の一家はね―
Housewife?
The victim's family was
the dam proponent's brother's...
その２年前に転落死した―
ダム誘致派の男の
弟一家に当たるのよ
...the one who died from
falling off a cliff two years prior.
And the fifth Cotton Drifting
Festival is, in other words...
そして ５年目の綿流しってのは
つまり…
...tonight.
今日なの
（圭一）えっ？
（知恵(ちえ)）じゃ 次の問題…
Now, how do you solve
this next problem?
What Tomitake-san said
was shocking to hear.
（圭一）富竹さんから聞いた話は
ショックだった
The series of strange deaths
in Hinamizawa every year.
この雛見沢で
毎年 起こった連続怪死事件
でも それは俺にとって
何の関係もない話だと思っていた
But I thought it had
nothing to do with me.
謎は全て解けた
I've solved the whole mystery.
The suspect is Rika-chan!
（魅音）犯人は梨花ちゃん
The weapon is poison!
凶器は毒物
The scene is the nurse's office!
犯行現場は医務室
Damn it!
（圭一）くそー！
（沙都子）外しましたわ！
I didn't get it!
I like gentle killing with poison.
毒物でジワリジワリがよいのです
（魅音）ヘヘヘッ… 余裕だね
（圭一）カ～ッ…
That was easy.
Next! Let's go to the next one!
次だ！ 次いくぞ！
（圭一）
…と その前に ちょっとトイレ
Oh, the bathroom before that.
Take your time
with your number two!
（魅音）
ゆっくりブリブリしておいで
（ﾚﾅ）もう 魅(み)ぃちゃん 下品！
Mi-chan, that's gross.
…と 見せかけて
ゆっくり作戦を練るか
Just kidding.
I'll take this time to strategize.
Maebara-kun?
（知恵）前原(まえばら)君
（圭一）うん？
（知恵）前原君に
お客さんがいらしてますよ
You have a visitor.
Please go to the entrance.
昇降口へ行ってください
A visitor?
お客さん？
（大石(おおいし)）フゥ…
（大石）
前原さんですか？ 前原圭一さん
Are you Maebara-san?
Keiichi Maebara-san?
（圭一）
そうですけど　どちらさまですか？
Yes, I am, and you are?
My car has air conditioning,
so why don't we talk in there?
私の車はエアコンが効いてますから
そっちで お話ししましょう
So what do you want from me?
（圭一）…で 俺に何の用ですか？
If you know anything about
this man, please tell me.
（大石）この男性のことで
ご存じのことがあったら―
教えてください
（圭一）えっ？
Is this Tomitake-san?
これ 富竹さん？
Then do you know this woman?
では
こちらの女性は分かりますか？
I don't know her name, but she
was with Tomitake-san last night.
（圭一）
えっと 名前は知りませんけど
ゆうべ
富竹さんと一緒にいた女の人です
（大石）この２人に
最後に会ったのは いつですか？
When was the last time
you saw these two?
（圭一）昨日
綿流しのお祭りの晩 話をしました
I talked to them last night
at the Cotton Drifting Festival.
何か気になったこととか
ありませんか？
Did you notice anything strange?
Please tell me
anything you know.
何でも結構です 話してください
Did something happen?
何か あったんですか？
That man in
the picture died last night.
（大石）その写真の男性は
ゆうべ お亡くなりになりました
When They Cry
He was killed on festival day.
（大石）綿流しの日に殺された
I'm sure you understand
what that means.
前原さんには
どういう意味があるのか―
分かりますよね？
（圭一）意味って…
What it means?
まさか オヤシロさまのたたり？
Could it be
Oyashiro-sama's curse?
What happened?
何があったんですか？
（大石）第１発見は―
Our patrol car found the body on the
way back from festival security duty.
祭りの警備を終えて帰宅中の
ウチのワゴンでした
時刻は24時５分前
The time was five to midnight.
場所は 街へ出る道路が
ちょうど舗装道路に変わる所
Where the road leads out
of town, the part that's paved.
街灯が ほとんどない道です
It had almost no lights.
In that darkness...
その暗闇の中で 路肩に倒れている
富竹さんを発見しましてね
...we found Tomitake-san's
body on the shoulder of the road.
地面いっぱいに
血と汚物が広がっていました
The ground was covered
with blood and filth.
（大石）
検視の結果 自分の爪で喉を…
The autopsy said
his nails slit his throat.
（圭一）爪？
（大石）富竹さんは何を思ったか…
Nails?
For whatever reason, he clawed
at his throat with all his power.
自分の爪で力いっぱいガリガリと…
そして 傷つけては いけない
大切な血管にまで爪が届き…
And he reached the artery
that should never be touched.
We suspected drugs, but we
couldn't detect anything like that.
薬物を疑いましたが
そういう たぐいの物は
検出できませんでした
However, we found many
external wounds on him.
（大石）ただ 体に
いくつもの外傷が発見されましてね
何者かに
暴行を受けた可能性があるんです
It's possible he was assaulted,
possibly by multiple people.
それも複数犯の可能性が…
（圭一）複数犯？
Multiple people?
It seems the estimated time of
death is between 21:00 and 23:00.
死亡推定時刻は
21時から23時ごろのようです
つまり 前原さんと別れて すぐに…
In other words,
right after you saw him.
- And the woman?
- She's missing.
女の人は？
（大石）行方不明です
事件に巻き込まれた可能性が
極めて高いようです
It's likely she's
involved in this incident.
At this rate, Jiro Tomitake-san...
このままでは
富竹ジロウさんは―
オヤシロさまのたたりで
死んだことになってしまいます
...will have died from
Oyashiro-sama's curse.
（大石）
綿流しの晩 神聖な儀式のとき―
During the sacred festival night...
無神経にカメラをバシャバシャ
撮っていたものだから―
...Oyashiro-sama got upset since
he was insensitively taking pictures.
オヤシロさまの怒りに触れた
It'll be reasoned like that.
そういう話になってしまうんですよ
（圭一）そんなことで…
That can't be...
Besides, people can't die from
divine punishment or curses.
（圭一）大体 バチとか
たたりとかで人が死ぬなんて…
（せきばらい）
そういうことですよ 前原さん
That's how it is, Maebara-san.
The help of a resident who doesn't
believe in curses is essential.
たたりを信じていない雛見沢の方の
協力が不可欠なのです
何でも結構です
不確かなもので かまいませんから
Anything is fine,
even if it's uncertain.
Oh, here's my phone number.
あっ これ 私の電話番号です
Everything we discussed
here is a secret...
（大石）今日
ここでした話は全てナイショです
...especially from
Sonozaki-san and her friends.
特に 園崎(そのざき)さんたちには 絶対
知られないようにしてください
うん？ 園崎って 魅音のことか？
Sonozaki? You mean Mion?
なんで？
Why?
I have no idea who's involved in
this village, or to what degree.
（大石）この村の誰が 一体
どれだけ関わっているのか―
全く分からないんですよ
That's why I don't want you
to tell the other villagers.
だからこそ
村人に口外してほしくないんです
No way...
そんな…
（大石）じゃ こう考えましょう
Then think of it this way...
たたりを妄信する村人の皆さんを
心配させたくないから ナイショ
Keep it secret so as to not worry
the curse-believing villagers.
そういうことで どうです？
How about thinking that way?
分かりました
All right...
（圭一）えっと…
（大石）興宮(おきのみや)署の大石です
Um...
Oishi of the Okinomiya police.
（圭一）あっ… あっ はい
Okay...
ゆうべ 眠れなかった
I couldn't sleep last night...
...because I had to hear what
Officer Oishi had to say.
あの大石という刑事の
話を聞いてしまったおかげで…
（魅音）
綿流しの晩に失踪したらしいよ
I heard she disappeared
on festival night...
But there were others too, right?
（ﾚﾅ）
…ほかにも いるんでしょう？
（魅音）
彼女が たたりに遭ったのか―
I'm not sure if it's the curse
or spiriting away by the demon.
鬼隠しに遭ったのかは
分かんないけどね
Spirited away by the demon?
What's that?
鬼隠し… 鬼隠しって？
There's another
one, right? Right?
Spirited away by the demon?
What's that?
オヤシロさまならね…
If it's Oyashiro-sama...
次はレナかな？
Am I next?
（魅音）
レナは ちゃんと帰ってきたよ
You came back though.
（ﾚﾅ）でも
悟史(さとし)君はダメだったんでしょう？
But Toshi-kun didn't, right?
（魅音）昔の話だよ
That's about the past.
Let's not talk about this anymore.
（魅音）もうやめよう この話
Shoot, I have to help
my uncle today!
いっけねえ！
今日 おじさんの手伝いの日だ！
Sorry, everyone!
No club activity today!
悪い みんな 今日は部活なし！
Helping your uncle?
You're dutiful, despite looks.
おじさんの手伝い？
ガラにもなく孝行なヤツだな
Weapon Suspect Crime scene
Helping your uncle?
You're dutiful, despite looks.
Weapon Suspect Crime scene
Sorry, everyone.
（魅音）じゃ ごめんね みんな
今日は これで帰るね
I'm going home for today.
Then club's cancelled today.
じゃ 今日は解散ですわね
Man...
チェッ…
Good day to you all.
それでは 皆さま ごきげんよう
（梨花）さよならです
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
また あしたね
（圭一）気ぃつけて帰れよ
Be careful on your way home.
あ～あ… このゲーム
楽しみにしていたのにな
I was looking
forward to this game.
Satoshi?
“悟史”？
Who's this?
誰だ？ これ
レナ
やっぱり このクラスからも―
Rena, have there been students
who transferred from this school?
転校しちゃった生徒って
いるのか？
（ﾚﾅ）うん 時々いるよ
Sometimes.
Did this Satoshi transfer too?
悟史ってヤツも転校してったのか？
Sorry, I don't really know.
（ﾚﾅ）ごめん よく知らないの
It seems he transferred
around the time I came here.
レナの転校と
入れ代わりだったみたいで…
So I didn't talk to him much.
だから
あんまり お話ししたことないの
（圭一）なあ レナ
Hey, Rena.
みんなは 俺に
ウソや隠し事なんかしてないよな？
You guys aren't lying to me
or keeping secrets, right?
うん？ してないよ 全然
No, we're not.
ウソだろう
That's a lie, right?
What do you mean, Keiichi-kun?
（ﾚﾅ）
どういう意味だろう？ 圭一君
（圭一）してるよな 俺に 隠し事
You're keeping something
secret from me, right?
圭一君こそ
レナたちにウソや隠し事を―
What about you?
Aren't you lying and keeping
secrets from us? Aren't you?
してないかな？ かな？
（圭一）えっ？
してないかな？ ウソや隠し事
Aren't you lying and
keeping secrets from us?
Aren't you?
してないかな？
してないよ ウソも隠し事も…
I'm not lying or keeping secrets.
ウソだよ
You're lying.
アッ… ど… どうしてウソだって…
W-Why do you say it's a lie?
During club yesterday...
（ﾚﾅ）
圭一君 昨日の部活のとき―
先生に呼ばれて
職員室に行ったって言ったよね？
...you said you were called to
the teacher's office, didn't you?
I know that you didn't
go to the teacher's office.
レナは知ってるよ
圭一君は
職員室になんか行かなかった
You were talking to someone
in a car near the school gate.
（ﾚﾅ）校門の所の車の中で
話をしてたよね？
With a man I didn't know.
知らない おじさんと…
誰？ あのおじさん
Who was he?
A-A person I don't know.
し… 知らない人だよ
Why would a stranger need you?
知らない人が
なんで圭一君に用があるの？
N-No clue.
お… 俺が知りたいよ！
Then what were
you talking about?
じゃ 何の話をしていたの？
みんなとは関係のない話だよ
Nothing to do with you.
ウソだ！
You're lying!
Just as you have
secrets and things to hide...
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君に
ナイショや隠し事があるように…
...so do we.
レナたちにだって あるんだよ
Y-Yeah...
フフッ…
行こう　だいぶ涼しくなってきたよ
Let's go.
It's getting a lot cooler.
Keiichi!
It's a call from the bookstore!
（藍子(あいこ)）
圭一 本屋さんから電話よ！
えっ？ 本屋？
Bookstore?
Hello?
Sorry for calling so late.
（大石）
夜分遅くに申し訳ありません
I'm Oishi from
the Okinomiya Bookstore.
私 興宮書房の大石と申します
えっ？ 大石さん？
Oishi-san?
So did anything
different happen?
（大石）どうです？
何か変わったことはありましたか？
Um, what does "spirited away
by the demon" mean?
（圭一）あの… 鬼隠しって
何のことか知ってますか？
It's an expression
unique to that village.
それはですね
この辺り独特の言い回しでしてね
It's the same meaning
as plain "spirited away."
世間さまでいう
“神隠し”と同じ意味ですよ
Spirited away...
神隠し…
Hinamizawa was feared as the
"village of the demon" long ago.
（大石）雛見沢は その昔
“鬼の住む里”って呼ばれて―
恐れられていたんですよ
鬼？ 鬼って 地獄にいる？
（大石）う～ん…
Demon? Like the ones in hell?
Um, more like
the man-eating ones.
…というよりは 人食い鬼ですな
里に下りてきて
人をさらって 食ってしまう
Those that come
to kidnap and eat people.
There was an old,
scary fairy tale like that.
（大石）…な～んて
怖い昔話があるんですよ
Rena and Mion
were talking about it.
（圭一）
レナと魅音が話してたんです
Oyashiro-sama and being
spirited away by a demon.
オヤシロさまなら
鬼隠しが どうとかって…
Maebara-san, you know
about the first incident, right?
（大石）前原さん
最初の事件 ご存じですよね？
バラバラ殺人の
The dismemberment?
Yes, of the six murderers,
one is still on the run, right?
ええ　６人の犯人のうち
１人は まだ逃走中なんですよね？
例えば それ 逃走中じゃなく
鬼隠しに遭ったとしたら？
What if they weren't on the run
but spirited away by the demon?
What about
the next year's accident?
その翌年の事故は どうなんです？
The dam proponent and
his wife dying in accidents.
誘致派の男と妻が
一緒に事故死したっていう…
Truthfully, only the husband
officially died in an accident.
実はですね 正式に事故死したのは
夫だけなんです
The wife's body
hasn't been found.
妻は死体も見つかっていません
What about the third year?
３年目は どうなんですか？
A priest dying of illness
and his wife by suicide.
神主は病死 妻は自殺ですよ
これも全く同じなんですよ
The same goes for that too.
あったのは遺書だけ
妻の死体は見つからなかった
The wife's body couldn't
be found, only a suicide note.
I'm not sure if I can call that
"spirited away by the demon..."
これらを鬼隠しと呼んでいいかは
ちょっと分かりませんがね
...but when it's Oyashiro-sama's
curse, one person goes missing.
オヤシロさまのたたりの度に
１人 行方不明になってます
Then the housewife who
was beaten to death last year...
じゃ 去年の主婦の撲殺事件は―
Did someone go missing?
誰か行方不明になりましたか？
犯人は逮捕されたんですよね？
The culprit was caught, right?
ええ 逮捕されてます
覚醒剤の常習者でしてね
Yes, he was arrested.
He was a drug addict.
But after the suspect
was arrested...
ですが
犯人逮捕から しばらくして―
...we found out that a child
of the victim had gone missing.
被害者宅の子供が 行方不明に
なっているのが分かったんです
えっ？
犯人は逮捕されているのに？
Even with the culprit arrested?
He died in the holding cell during the
inquiry, so the truth's in the dark.
取調中に 拘置所で死にましてね
真相は闇の中なんですよ
What about the missing child?
行方不明になった子供って…
The child's a year older than you
and named Satoshi Hojo-kun.
年は あなたの１つ上で
名前は北条(ほうじょう)悟史君
えっ？ 悟史？
Satoshi?
He was in your
school till last year.
（大石）あなたの学校に
去年まで通っていました
You'll be sitting there.
He was in your
school till last year.
（知恵）席は そこです
転校した生徒の席ですけどね
It's the seat of
a student who transferred.
（蹴る音）
（伊知郎(いちろう)）おい 圭一！
Hey, Keiichi. Open up here.
（伊知郎）
ちょっと ここを開けてくれ
Sorry, my dad's here.
That'll be it for tonight.
すみません 親父(おやじ)が来ました
今夜は これぐらいで
Please let me know again if
something happens. Well then...
（大石）
何かあったら また教えてください
Hey, hurry and open up!
Please let me know again if
something happens. Well then...
では…
（伊知郎）お～い 早く開けてくれ
I'm opening it now.
（圭一）今 開けるから
うん？ なに？ それ
What's that?
（伊知郎）もう はぐらかすなよ
Oh, don't hide things.
Rena-chan was just here, right?
I figured I'd bring you some tea.
（伊知郎）さっき
レナちゃんが来てたじゃないか
せっかくだから
お茶でもって思ったんだけど…
（伊知郎）
あれ？ すれ違いだったかな？
Hm, maybe I missed her.
レナが…
（伊知郎）隠すなよ
Rena was...
Don't hide it. Weren't you
talking to her the whole time?
ずっと レナちゃんと
おしゃべりしてたんだろう？
（圭一）
２階に上がったの 父さん 見たの？
Did you see her
walk up the stairs?
（伊知郎）ああ 見たよ
Yeah, I did.
（伊知郎）圭一の部屋は 階段を
上がって すぐだよって教えたよ
I told her your room
was straight up the stairs.
W-What are you doing, Keiichi?
（伊知郎）な… 何だよ 圭一！
テレなくてもいいだろう
Don't be embarrassed.
Rena was definitely
here at that time.
（圭一）
そのとき 確かにレナは来ていた
そして 俺の部屋の前で…
She was right outside my room...
...and heard my
conversation with Oishi-san.
大石さんと俺の会話を…
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What you can see
is the false whereabouts.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
あなたに見えるのは 偽りの居場所
What you can see
is the false whereabouts.
there is a blank look.
そこに見えるのは
うつろな まなざし
What I can see
is repeated sadness.
私に見えるのは 繰り返す悲しみ
When They Cry.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Three, Suspicion.
Chapter Three, Suspicion
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Three, Suspicion.
あなたは信じられますか？
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Three, Suspicion
Can you believe it?